Illia Illiashenko

Senior Software Engineer

Warsaw Poland, illia@illiashenko.dev, linkedin.com/in/theredx

rofessional Summary
am a software development professional with 5+ years of experience. During this time, I have worked on ojects of various scales and complexities, specializing in TypeScript and JavaScript. My main expertise is eveloping applications with React and building front-end application architecture. In my recent projects, I have sen instrumental in improving application architecture and developing key front-end features.
KILLS
peScript, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Next js, Redux, MobX, Context, Nest js, SQL, Postgres, Git, CSS in JS, CSS, Material UI, GitHub Actions, AWS, Bitbucket pipelines, Jest, Cypress, Axe linter, Playwright, Relay, pollo, Storybook, Sonar, Jenkins, GraphQL, React Testing Library, Webpack, Parcel, Docker, Docker compose

Experience

Tailwind, Express, Koa.

SoftServe - Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2021 - Current

Project: Atlassian - Employee onboarding app

- Designed and implemented a scalable front-end architecture, following modern best practices.
- Maintained technical documentation to support team collaboration and onboarding.
- Diagnosed and resolved complex issues, improving application reliability and feature performance.
- Delivered high-quality, unit-tested features aligning with customer timelines and expectations.
- Collaborated closely with engineers to optimize system integration and ensure seamless frontend-backend communication.
- Managed deployments of new releases, coordinating feature updates and critical fixes.
- Ensured compliance with Atlassian's standards for accessibility, performance, data privacy, and automated testing.

Tech stack: React, TypeScript, GraphQL, Relay, Atlassian Design System, Bitbucket pipelines, Axe linter, CSS-in-JS, Playwright, React Testing Library, Jest, Storybook, Sonar.

Project: LinkSquares - Finalize product

- Refactored a multi-step wizard flow, optimizing performance by managing state with Redux and local storage, significantly reducing backend load and enhancing user experience.
- Mentored new developers during onboarding, providing guidance on architecture, workflows, and solving complex development challenges.
- Contributed to front-end architecture improvements by migrating portions of business logic from backend to client-side, resulting in a more responsive UI.
- Implemented secure user authentication via Okta, integrating centralized login functionality across the web application.

Tech stack: React, Ruby on rails, Context, Material UI, Styled Components, SCSS, Materialize CSS, Onlyoffice, React Testing Library, Webpack, Teamcity, vite.

Project: Rotary International - Management system

- Maintained comprehensive documentation of development work, facilitating knowledge sharing among team members.
- Enhanced software functionality by identifying and resolving complex technical issues.
- Delivered unit-tested systems within customer-prescribed timeframes.
- Coordinated with other engineers to evaluate and improve software and hardware interfaces.
- Coordinated deployments of new software, feature updates and fixes.
- Enhanced user experience by implementing responsive web designs and optimizing performance.

Tech stack: React, TypeScript, Node.js, Context, GraphQL, Apollo, Okta, Tailwind CSS, React Testing Library, Jest, Cypress, Express, Gatsby, fp-ts, Storybook.

NIX - Software Engineer

Mar 2020 - Oct 2021

Project: Elsevier - Document editor app

- Consistently met project deadlines by effectively managing time and prioritizing tasks according to importance.
- Analyzed proposed technical solutions based on customer requirements.
- Developed scalable and maintainable code, ensuring long-term stability of the software.
- Developed reusable components that significantly reduced development effort on multiple projects.
- Refactored legacy codebases for improved maintainability, paving the way for easier future updates.

Tech stack: React, Redux, CKEditor5, SASS, Node.js, Express, Webpack, Jest, React Testing Library, Karma, Jenkins, Sonar.

Freelance Oct 2019 - Mar 2020

Project: Admin UI for inventory control in warehouses

- Developed custom web applications, resulting in tailored solutions for client.
- Implemented trello-like dashboard with drag & drop feature and state management.
- Worked with complex business logic, delivered stable releases.
- Maintained deployment process and stable dev and production environments.

Education	
Kharkiv National University of Radioelectronics	
Bachelor of Science - Software Engineering	

Languages		

Ukrainian - Native language

Russian - Native language

English - B2 (Upper intermediate)